# Pooja Patel

London, ON | Phone: 226-637-5003 | poojapatel6480@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

User Support oriented Technical Support Specialist with four years of experience working on help desks and in remote environments. Gave customer support to handle technical difficulties through a series of troubleshooting tasks and knowledge-based research. Excellent skills in system analysis, diagnostics, troubleshooting, and conflict resolution. Excellent organization and problem-solving abilities. Works well in team settings and has a strong work ethic. Professional with a strong focus on detail and a post-graduate degree in business and information systems architecture.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Customer Service Advisor Feb 2023 – Present

Concentrix (Rogers)

- Reviewed individual customer cases providing mediation on behalf of client for consideration outside policies and procedures.
- Documented new case or updated case file information using Concentrix quality standards.
- Clarify customer requirements; probe for understanding; use decision-support tools and resources to resolve customer issues that are non-standard/unstructured and require some clarification or conceptual thinking.
- Maintain broad knowledge of client products and/or services.
- Prepare complete and accurate work including appropriately notating of accounts as required.
- Participate in activities designed to improve customer satisfaction and business performance.

#### **Customer Experience Salesfloor Associate**

Oct 2021 - Present

Walmart - London, ON

- Provided customer service by acknowledging the customer and identifying customer needs.
- Provided 100 percent Customer satisfaction.
- Located merchandise and resolved member issues and concerns, promoting the company's products and services.
- Acted as department manager whenever needed by the management.
- Managed more than 10 people working under me and Provided training to new employees.
- Registered sales on a cash register by scanning items, itemizing, and totaling customers' purchases and walked them through our MasterCard program.

# **Technical Support Representative**

Jul 2019 – Apr 2021

HUDL India Private Limited, Mumbai, India

- Took calls of customers and provided professional technical help and troubleshooting guidance for network, Internet, cable, digital phone, computer/laptop (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 8, 10, and Mac OS), webmail, printers, repeater pods, and TV modem problems.
- Communicated with clients experiencing technical difficulties via email and phone in order to identify and document problems.
- Diagnosed and addressed technological issues that consumers confront.
- Effectively disseminated technical knowledge and communicates with non-technical audiences.
- Used internal software, tools, and instructions to investigate client problems and execute solutions.
- Practical expertise with Citrix virtual apps and desktops, VMware workstation, Active Directory, Outlook, and Office 365.
- Using the Service Now ticketing system, document customer records with a log of problems and solutions for use by other Technical Support Representatives.
- Educate customers on the entire value of our clients' products and services and look for ways to improve our business and elevate customer
  experiences.
- Maintain good service levels by using time management and multitasking skills.

# **Technical Support Analyst**

Dec 2017 - June 2019

Patel and Associates - Mumbai, India

- Answers clients' questions by recognizing problems, finding solutions, and assisting them through corrective steps.
- Enhances client references through the creation and maintenance of documentation.
- Contributes to the creation of client training programs by recognizing learning difficulties and recommending instructional language.
- Helps clients with disabilities by recommending gadgets and techniques.
- Avoids legal issues by monitoring service agreement compliance.
- Supporting end users in a 1-1 capability, ideally fixing problems remotely
- Enhanced system performance by identifying issues and recommending fixes.
- Resolved all customer issues by understanding their needs and providing them relevant suggestions and product.
- Troubleshooting email issues, hardware software setup, Resolving username and password difficulties.
- Organized meetings with the clients and gathered user stories and analyzed their requirements and provided solution.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Helpdesk Support: Hardware assembly, Software installation, Drivers installation, Network Printers, Tablet, MAC PCs, Windows PCs, VPN Tokens, External Hard drives, Mobile devices, USB Flash drives, Access Points, Routers, Modems, Microsoft Office 365.
- Database Systems: SQL, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server
- Operating Systems & Machines: Windows (98, XP, Vista, 10, 11), MAC OS, Android, IOS
- Microsoft Server Functionalities: Active Directory, SharePoint, Exchange, Teams, Outlook, Database storage server, Windows Deployment Services (WDS)
- Virtualization: VMware Fusion, parallel Desktop, OracleVM Virtual Box and VMware Workstation, Hyper V

#### SOFT SKILLS

- Effective troubleshooting and reverse engineering skills with Precise Time management
- Dynamic, multi-tasker and self-directed professional with Optimistic attitude even under pressure and a great team-spirit
- Proactive at working with cross-functional teams to drive Application Operations by utilizing process knowledge.
- Creative and quick at logic development, Flexible to learn new technologies.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Smart Mirror: A Reflective Portal to Increase Productivity | University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

- The smart mirror is the modern-day integration of accessing services hands-free while doing daily chores; thus, increasing productivity substantially.
- The smart mirror automatically recognizes that there is a user present and becomes active using the web camera inside the two-way mirror.

#### Attendance management system | Fanshawe college, London Ontario

- The popularity of smartphones has increased over the years. The current attendance system is quite time-consuming and requires a manual workload i.e., the paper-based attendance system. So, we need a system that doesn't require any extra human effort. We created an application and a mobile-friendly website.
- Our proposed solution is mainly based on QR codes.

# PAPER PUBLISHED

# Smart Mirror: A Reflective Portal to Increase Productivity

IOSR Journal of Engineering (IOSR JEN) www.iosrjen.org ISSN (e): 2250-3021, ISSN (p): 2278-8719 PP 45-48 <a href="https://iosrjen.org/Papers/Conf.19018-2019/INFT/Volume-7/13.%2045-48.pdf">https://iosrjen.org/Papers/Conf.19018-2019/INFT/Volume-7/13.%2045-48.pdf</a>

# **EDUCATION**

Post-graduation in Business and Information Systems Architecture | Fanshawe College-(CGPA:4.0/4.2)

May 2021- Dec 2022

• Coursework: End user Operations, Web technologies, Management, Azure

Bachelor of Engineering in Information technology | Mumbai University-(CGPA: 7.02/10.0)

Jun 2015 - Jun 2019

• Coursework: Networking, Big Data, Visualisation